sram.com 2017-02-20

# Privacy Policy & Terms of Use | SRAM

## Privacy Policy & Terms of Use

Please read carefully before using this site. This site is owned and operated by SRAM, LLC together with its subsidiaries and affiliates (collectively "We", "Us" or "Our"). By using this site, you signify your agreement to the Privacy Policy and Terms of Use. If you do not agree with these terms, please do not use this site. We reserve the right, at Our discretion, to change, modify, add, or remove portions of these terms at any time. Your continued use of this site following changes to these terms will signify your acceptance of the revised terms.

## Privacy Policy

Your privacy on the Internet is important to Us. As a part of the operation of this site, We gather certain types of information about users. We want you to know the types of information We gather and what we do with it.

## Information We Collect

We collect two general types of information from users: personal data (such as names and e-mail addresses); and aggregate data (such as information about traffic patterns on this site; for example, how many users log into this site on a daily basis).

## Personal Data

Personal data is collected when users provide information to Us, for example in registering for electronic newsletters or other membership services, in answering surveys, purchasing items from the online store, and/or registering for contests and other promotional opportunities provided by Us. When you register or request information on this site, We generally need your to provide your name, e-mail address, mailing address, day phone number and credit card information (only when ordering products at the online store), as well as create a username and password. In addition, if you send Us personal correspondence, such as e-mails or letters, We may collect such information into a file specific to you.

## Aggregated Information and Usage Information

Aggregate information, such as which page users access and information volunteered by users, such as survey information and/or site registration information, is collected through various methods. In the course of using Our site, We also automatically track certain information about you. This information includes the URL that you just came from, which URL you next go to, what browser your are using, and your IP address. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you're surfing the web. Web servers, the computers that "serve up" web pages, automatically identify your computer by its IP address, and when you request a page from Us, Our servers log your IP address. We do not link IP addresses to anything personally identifiable, so although your session will be logged, you will remain anonymous to Us.

## Use of Cookies

This site also uses "cookies" to collect information. A cookie is a small data file that most major websites write to your hard drive for record keeping purposes when you visit them. Cookies allow Us to measure activity on the various areas of this site and to improve your user experience, for example by remembering your passwords and viewing preferences, thus allowing you to visit various parts of this site without re-registering. Cookies also allow Us to measure activity on the site and make improvements and updates based on which areas are popular and which are not. We do not use cookies to retrieve information from your computer that was not originally sent in a cookie. Please note: except for personal information voluntarily provided by you (e.g. during membership registration or a contest). We do not use information transferred through cookies for any promotional or marketing purposes, nor is the information shared with any third parties whatsoever. You may occasionally get cookies from Our advertisers, which is standard in the internet industry. We do not control these cookies, and these cookies are not subject to this Privacy Policy.

Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies. If you would prefer, you can set yours to refuse cookies or to alert you when cookies are being sent. However, it is possible that some parts of a site, such as a member-only area and shopping, contest and game areas, will not function properly if you do so.

## Use of Information Collected by Us

We use both the personal and aggregated and usage information We collect for multiple purposes. For example, We collect this information for fulfilling orders and prizes, administering information requests and providing information services, tracking/verifying compliance with Our policies as well as federal, state and local laws, and for editorial and feedback solicitation purposes. We may use your e-mail address and, in rare situations, your mailing address or phone number, to contact you regarding customer service issues or billing matters. Personal and aggregated information is also used to: improve the content of the Store; perform system administration activities; customize the content and/or layout of the Store for each individual user; and notify users about updates to the Store or promotional offers or opportunities that We believe will be of interest to you. We will always try to provide you with an opportunity to decline this service when such information is requested from you online. If you later decide you would rather not receive this information, or would like to opt-out of any other information request or distribution, you may also update your account information on the applicable portion of this site or simply reply to any e-mail sent to you and type UNSUBSCRIBE as the subject of your reply or in the message of the e-mail. We may also use your information and activity on the site to resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems and enforce Our Terms of Use.

## Kids

We recognize that parents, guardians, or other adults often purchase our products for family use, including use by minors. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13 for marketing purposes, but because some information is collected electronically, it can appear to be the personal information of the purchaser of the product, and will be treated as such by this privacy policy. If a child under 13 submits personal information to Us and We learn that that personal information is the information of a child under 13, we will attempt to delete the information as soon as possible.

## Disclosure of Collected Information to Third Parties

We do not sell, trade, rent or otherwise provide your personal data to third parties without prior permission from you, provided however, that third parties does not include Our subsidiaries, affiliates, licensees, partners, website hosting partners or other parties who assist Us in operating this site. We may, however, share your data in an aggregate format, as well as aggregate usage information, with third parties for both advertising and promotional purposes. Further, We cooperate with all law enforcement inquires, and with all third parties, to enforce their intellectual property or other legal rights.

## Links to Other Sites

It is important to note that this site might contain links to other sites, and that those sites may not follow the same privacy policies as Us. For instance, if you clicked on an advertisement on Store, this might take you away from this site and to an entirely different site. This includes links to advertisers, bicycle dealers, content providers, and business partners, who may use Our name and/or logos as a result of a co-branding or other agreement. These sites may send their own cookies to you, and may collect data and make uses of it that We would not. We do not control these sites or use, or bear any responsibility or liability for them.

## Security

The security of all personally identifiable information associated with users of this site is of great concern to Us. We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information. Once We receive your transmission, We use reasonable efforts to ensure its security on Our systems. When credit card information is transmitted, We use SSL (secure socket layer) encryption technology. Any account information you enter on this site is password-protected so that only you can access it. You should not divulge your password or user identification number to anyone. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while We strive to protect your personal information, We can't ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to Us, and you do so at your own risk.

## Terms of Use

Ownership; Restrictions on Use of Materials The entire content included in this site, including but not limited to text, graphics or code, is owned by or licensed to Us. We reserve the right to make changes to the content of this site at any time without notice, including with respect to our products, equipment, specifications, models, colors, and materials. You may download, view, and print text and graphics from this site, provided that such content is only used for informational, non-commercial purposes, and is not modified or altered in any way. Except as expressly provided herein, you may not use, download, upload, copy, print, display, perform, reproduce, publish, license, post, transmit or distribute any information or content from this site in whole or in part without Our prior written permission. SRAM, RockShox, etc. (Maria, please insert our marks) are trademarks or registered trademarks of SRAM, LLC. Other trademarks, service marks, slogans, logos and trade names identified on this site are either Our trademarks or trademarks of a third party licensor or other provider. None of these marks, names or logos may be used without the prior written consent of their owner.

## SRAM trademark list and acknowledgements

These are registered trademarks of SRAM, LLC:

1:1®, AVID®, BLACKBOX®, BOXXER®, DOUBLETAP®, ELITA®, FIRECREST®, FIREX®, GRIP SHIFT®, GXP®, HAMMERSCHMIDT®, HOLZFELLER®, HUSSEFELT®, i-Motion®, JUICY®, OMNIUM®, PowerLock®, QUARQ®, REBA®, ROCK SHOX®, RUKTION®, SERVICE COURSE®, SID®, SINGLE DIGIT®, SPEED DIAL®, SPEED WEAPONRY®, SRAM APEX®, SRAM FORCE®, SRAM RED®, SRAM RIVAL®, SRAM VIA®, SRAM®, STYLO®, The Power of Bicycles®, TORPEDO®, TRUVATIV®, World Bicycle Relief®, ZEDTECH®, ZIPP®

These are trademarks of SRAM, LLC:

101™, 202™, 303™, 404s™, 808s™, 2x10™, ABLC™, Air Guides™, AKA™, AL-7050-TV™, Argyle™, Automatix™, Bend Zone™, BB™, BB5™, BB7™, BB30™, blaze™, Boobar™, BoxGuide™, Carbon Bridge™, Carbon Crown-Steerer™, Centera™, Code™, Contact Point Adjustment™, Deep Stroke Modulation™, DESCENDANT™, Direct Route Technology™, D.i.R.T.™, Domain™, DropStop™, Dual Air™, DualDrive™, Dual Flow™, Dual Position Air™, Dual Position Coil™, Elixir™, Exact Actuation™, Fixed Coil™, FR-5™, G2 Clean Sweep™, G3 Clean Sweep™, HollowPin™, Hot Rod™, Howitzer™, HSX™, HS1™, i-Light™, Integrated Reservoir™, Kage™, Komfy™, Long Travel Dual Air™, Lyrik™, MatchMaker™, Maxle™, Mission Control™, Monarch™ & Monarch Plus™, Monoblok™, Motion Control™, MRX™, noir™, OCT™, OpenGlide™, Overdrive™, Poploc™, Power Bulge™, PowerChain™, Powered by SRAM™, PowerGlide™, PowerLink™, PowerMeter Pro™, Power Reserve Geometry™, Pressfit, Pushloc™, R2C™, Reach Adjust™, Recon™, RedRum™, reverb™, Revelation™, Rim Wrangler™, RISE™, RoulEuroper™, S27™, S30™, S40™, S60™, S80™, Sag Gradients™, SEKTOR™, ShiftGuide™, Shorty™, SL™, SLC2™, SL145™, SLSPEED™, Solo Air™, Speed Lube™, SRAM P5™, SRAM S7™, SRAM T3™, SRAM TRX™, SRAM X.0™, SRAM X.5™, SRAM X.7™, SRAM X.9™, Sub-9™, Super-9™, Supercork™, Superlight™, Supertech™, TaperBore™, Tool-Free Reach Adjust™, Top-loading Pads™, Totem™, Travel Gradients™, Tri-Align™, Turnkey™, VCLC™, Vivid™, Vivid Air™, VukaAero™, VukaBull™, VukaClip™, Vukar2c™, VukaSprint™, WiFLi™, X-GLIDE™, XLOC™, X9™, X7™, X5™, XC™, XO™, XX™, XX Motion Control™, Zero Loss™

Specifications and colors subject to change without prior notice.

Trademarks owned by other companies that must be acknowledged:

PowerTap® is a registered trademark of Saris Cycling Group, Inc.  
Shimano® is a registered trademark of Shimano Inc. Japan  
Campagnolo® is a registered trademark of Campagnolo S.R.L.  
Castelli® is a registered trademark of Castelli S.p.A.  
Headsweats® is a registered trademark of Alan Romick  
Coolmax® is a registered trademark of INVISTA North America S.A.R.L.   
TORX® is a registered trademark of Acument Intellectual Properties, LLC  
Pantone® is a registered trademark of Pantone, Inc.   
Sapim® is a registered trademark of SAPIM, naamloze vennootschap  
Easton® is a registered trademark of Easton Sports Inc.  
Bontrager® and Aeolus® are registered trademarks of Trek Bicycle Corporation  
HED® is a registered trademark of Hed Cycling Products, Inc.  
FFWD® is a registered trademark of Henk Schipper   
Planet X® is a registered trademark of David Loughran  
Tour de France® is a registered trademark of Societe du Tour de France  
Vittoria® is a registered trademark of Vittoria Industries North America, LLC  
Cannondale® is a registered trademark of Cycling Sports Group, Inc.  
Grilon® is a registered trademark of EMS-Chemie AG, Switzerland HG  
IG® is a registered trademarks of Shimano Inc., Japan  
Empilon® is registered trademark of HO Tai Industrial Co.  
Hayes® is a registered trademark of Hayes Brakes LLC  
Magura® is a registered trademark of Gustav Magenwirth GmbH  
Trek® is a registered trademark of Trek Bicycle Corporation  
Kraton® is a registered trademark of Kraton Polymers  
Quarq® is a registered trademark of Quarq Technology, Inc.   
Garmin® is a registered trademark of Garmin, Ltd.  
iOS® is a registered trademark of Cisco Technology, Inc.

Copyright notice: Copyright © 2016 SRAM LLC

## Forums

"Forum" means a chat area, bulletin board, or e-mail function offered as part of this site. Harassment in any manner or form on this site, including via e-mail and chat or by obscene or abusive language, is strictly forbidden. You shall not upload to, distribute through, or otherwise publish on or through this site any content that is libelous, defamatory, infringing, obscene, pornographic, threatening, invasive of privacy or publicity rights, abusive, illegal, or otherwise objectionable that would constitute or encourage a criminal offense, violate the rights of any party, or otherwise give rise to liability or violate any law. The Forums shall be used only in a noncommercial manner. You shall not, without Our express approval, distribute or otherwise publish any material containing any solicitation of funds, promotion, advertising, or solicitation for goods or services. By uploading materials to any Forum or submitting any materials to Us, you automatically grant us a perpetual, royalty-free, irrevocable, nonexclusive right and license, subject only to express restrictions set forth in Our Privacy Policy, to use, reproduce, modify, adapt, publish, translate, create derivative works from, and distribute such materials or incorporate such materials into any form, medium, or technology now known or later developed throughout the world.

We do not and cannot review all communications and materials posted to or created by users accessing Our site and are not in any manner responsible for the content of these communications and materials. We reserve the right, however, to block or remove communications or materials that We determine to be (a) abusive, defamatory, or obscene, (b) fraudulent, deceptive, or misleading, (c) in violation of a copyright, trademark or other intellectual property right of another, or (d) offensive or otherwise unacceptable to Us in Our sole discretion.

## Disclaimer

THE CONTENT IN THIS SITE IS PROVIDED "AS IS" AND WITHOUT WARRANTIES OF ANY KIND EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED. TO THE FULLEST EXTENT PERMISSIBLE PURSUANT TO APPLICABLE LAW, WE DISCLAIM ALL WARRANTIES, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NON-INFRINGEMENT. WE DO NOT WARRANT THAT THE OPERATION OF THIS SITE WILL BE UNINTERRUPTED OR ERROR-FREE, THAT DEFECTS WILL BE CORRECTED, OR THAT THIS SITE OR THE SERVER THAT MAKES IT AVAILABLE ARE FREE OF VIRUSES OR OTHER HARMFUL COMPONENTS. WE DO NOT WARRANT OR MAKE ANY REPRESENTATIONS REGARDING THE USE OR THE RESULTS OF THE USE OF THE MATERIALS IN THIS SITE IN TERMS OF THEIR CORRECTNESS, ACCURACY, RELIABILITY, OR OTHERWISE. APPLICABLE LAW MAY NOT ALLOW THE EXCLUSION OF IMPLIED WARRANTIES, SO THE ABOVE EXCLUSION MAY NOT APPLY TO YOU.
